Guide to the Allan H. Treman papers, 1824-1967
Treman, Allan H. papers, 1824-1967
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Allan H. Treman papers, 1824-1967.
3612
Allan H., Treman 1899-1975.
3 cubic ft.
Legal documents; letters; news clippings; photographs; slides; programs; scrapbooks; audiotapes and transcripts; and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes legal documents; letters; news clippings; photographs; slides; programs; scrapbooks, including one mostly concerning Robert H. Treman; maps; and material used in compiling As I Remember: Recollections of Allan H. Treman (ed. Joyce H. Finch), including news clippings, transcripts of tape recordings, nine tapes, and other items. Also a hand-colored map of C.U. campus by Richard Rummell.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Allan H. Treman was the son of Robert H. and Mary McLallan Treman. He attended Cornell University and was a lawyer, law teacher, and counsel to Cornell University. He was an active public figure in Ithaca and Tompkins County, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes legal documents; letters; news clippings; photographs; slides; programs; scrapbooks, including one mostly concerning Robert H. Treman; maps; and material used in compiling As I Remember: Recollections of Allan H. Treman (ed. Joyce H. Finch), including news clippings, transcripts of tape recordings, nine tapes, and other items. Also a hand-colored map of C.U. campus by Richard Rummell.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Treman, Allan H., 1899-1975.; Rummell, Richard, 1848-1924; Treman, Mary McLallan.; Treman, Robert H. (Robert Henry), 1858-1937.; Cornell University.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.).; Tompkins County (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Legal documents re: Abner Treman, Town of Ulysses, 1833-1853 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Covering letter from Dorman Purdy, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters, 1939-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Newsclippings, 1937-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Photographs and stereoptic slides (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Miscellany: programs, scorecards, photogravure, etc. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Wood-bound volume: The Life of Jesus of Nazareth: Eighty Pictures by William Hole. London: Eyre & Spottswoode, Ltd.(from Jerusalem), 1910 (Box 1)
- Framed sketch of Hiram Corson, 1912 (Box 1)
- A.H.T.'s scrapbook, includes programs and newsclippings, 1917-1919 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook, newsclipping and photos, 1917-1919 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Material used in compiling Treman book, As I Remember (i.e., newspaper clippings, transcripts of cassette tapes) (Box 3)
- Framed sketch of plan of Cornell Park, Ithaca, N.Y. by Wm. Webster, 1896 (Box 4)
- Scrapbook made for Allan H. Treman by his mother, 1939; mostly newsclippings about Robert H. Treman, ca. 1890-1959 (Box 4)
- Scrapbook containing newsclipping, photos, 1949-1967 (Volume 1)
- Panorama view from South Hill looking at Cayuga Lake and surrounding area, ca. 1900's (Map-case Folder 1)
- Panorama of Ithaca flood conditions, taken from West Hill toward South East, 1903 (Map-case Folder 1)
- Hand-colored painting of Cornell campus, by Richard Rummell, 1906 (Map-case Folder 1)
- Allan H. Treman certificate from U.S. Supreme Court, Undated (Map-case Folder 1)